<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Getting Technical]]></title>
  <link href="http://twitchtv.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://twitchtv.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-03T16:33:09-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://twitchtv.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[TwitchTV]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Different Features, Equal KPI's]]></title>
    <link href="http://twitchtv.github.com/blog/2012/07/03/mobile-analytics/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-03T14:53:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://twitchtv.github.com/blog/2012/07/03/mobile-analytics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last January we were really excited when Jorge joined Twitch to build us an Android app.  As a project manager a key question I helped answer was what to build for the initial release.  I pushed for a tight spec for the v1 Android, and I was excited to see how the spartan Android app’s numbers would stack up to the full featured IOS app.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The results are stable nearly identical key metrics: retention and minutes-watched per unique user.  The seven-day user retention are basically the same across the board; iPhone has 34% retention, iPad and Android both have 35% retention.  The minutes-watched per daily unique user are similar on all the apps; iPhone has 35, iPad 44, and Android 40 minutes per day.  The android app&#8217;s feature set consists of live video, a quality selector (480p, 720p, etc), search, and directories.  The IOS app was released with many additional features available upon login: a directory of channels you follow, push notifications, and chat.</p>

<p>We are not a “mobile-first” company; our users were familiar with Twitch before they downloaded the app.  There is solid evidence that our app growth comes primarily from pushover through alerts that encourage Twitch visitors on mobile devices to download the apps. The pushover doubled the growth in daily active IOS users and increased the growth in iPad daily actives by a factor of 20.</p>

<p>As we add features one at a time, we will see what actually affects Twitch mobile user behavior.  We could have delayed giving users something they value highly, the simple Android app, and that would have been a big waste.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Transitional Year]]></title>
    <link href="http://twitchtv.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/a-transitional-year/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-30T16:44:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://twitchtv.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/a-transitional-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Next week is E3, which marks a year since we first launched TwitchTV. What a year it has been!
This post serves to provide an answer to the question I field the most when out and about talking about
what we do: &#8220;What is the difference between TwitchTV and JustinTV?&#8221;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I joined at the end of April &#8216;12, I&#8217;d been a fan and user of JustinTV for a long time, as a technologist I highly
admired their large scale video system, after reading
<a href="http://highscalability.com/blog/2010/3/16/justintvs-live-video-broadcasting-architecture.html">the coverage on high scalability</a>
I knew these guys were serious business. An <a href="http://ossareh.posterous.com/interviews-are-tough-code-submissions-are-har">intense interview later</a>
and I was the only developer of a new website called &#8220;Xarth&#8221;.</p>

<p>The primary task on hand was to convert all the JTV pages over to a new layout, displaying just the gaming subsection of
content available on JustinTV. It turned out that live video game streaming was taking off at an insane rate,
relative to the rest of JTV gaming looked like a rocket ship. &#8220;Xarth&#8221; was our attempt to make those gamers happy.</p>

<p>After a few weeks hacking on this conversion it was decided we launch the new site during E3 2011. I threw
myself at finishing pages and re-factoring various features to support being run on two sites. At few days prior
to launch we decided to change the name of &#8220;Xarth&#8221; to &#8220;TwitchTV&#8221;, we raced to fix all of our branding for E3 and launched!
The rest is history; we&#8217;ve been <a href="http://www.google.com/trends/?q=twitch.tv,own3d.tv,machinima.com&amp;ctab=0&amp;geo=all&amp;date=ytd&amp;sort=0"><em>killing it</em></a>
ever since.</p>

<p>So with the history out of the way, I think it is easiest to explain the difference as &#8220;TwitchTV is JustinTV with a
strong product:market fit and super passionate users&#8221;. JustinTV is now maintained by a small team within the company
with the rest of our technical focus being on building what our gaming users and broadcasters need. It is amazing
to build software for tech savvy users, they understand the pain in technology, they use modern browsers(!!!) and
as avid gamers ourselves they give us content that we enjoy! We all refer to ourselves as &#8220;TwitchTV&#8221; now&#8230;</p>

<p>Next week is E3, we&#8217;ve gone from being a company launching to being a player in the industry in a year. We&#8217;re stacked
with super exiciting announcements next week, we&#8217;ll discuss the technology behind over the next few posts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
