<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Analytics | Getting Technical]]></title>
  <link href="http://twitchtv.github.com/blog/categories/analytics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://twitchtv.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-05T11:18:04-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://twitchtv.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[TwitchTV]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Different Features, Equal KPI's]]></title>
    <link href="http://twitchtv.github.com/blog/2012/07/03/mobile-analytics/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-03T14:53:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://twitchtv.github.com/blog/2012/07/03/mobile-analytics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last January we were really excited when Jorge joined Twitch to build us an Android app.  As a project manager a key question I helped answer was what to build for the initial release.  I pushed for a tight spec for the v1 Android, and I was excited to see how the spartan Android app’s numbers would stack up to the full featured IOS app.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The results are stable nearly identical key metrics: retention and minutes-watched per unique user.  The seven-day user retention are basically the same across the board; iPhone has 34% retention, iPad and Android both have 35% retention.  The minutes-watched per daily unique user are similar on all the apps; iPhone has 35, iPad 44, and Android 40 minutes per day.  The android app's feature set consists of live video, a quality selector (480p, 720p, etc), search, and directories.  The IOS app was released with many additional features available upon login: a directory of channels you follow, push notifications, and chat.</p>

<p>We are not a “mobile-first” company; our users were familiar with Twitch before they downloaded the app.  There is solid evidence that our app growth comes primarily from pushover through alerts that encourage Twitch visitors on mobile devices to download the apps. The pushover doubled the growth in daily active IOS users and increased the growth in iPad daily actives by a factor of 20.</p>

<p>As we add features one at a time, we will see what actually affects Twitch mobile user behavior.  We could have delayed giving users something they value highly, the simple Android app, and that would have been a big waste.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
